priceme.co.nz 2019-02-04

# Privacy Policy

At PriceMe, we strive to develop innovative services to better serve our users. We recognize that privacy is an important issue, so we design and operate our services with the protection of your privacy in mind. This Privacy Policy outlines the types of personal information we gather when you use PriceMe's services, as well as some of the steps we take to safeguard it. 

The following principles apply to the personally identifying information we ask for and that you provide:

  * We will respect your privacy.
  * We use personal information to deliver a better shopping comparison service.
  * We’re committed to honesty and transparency, so you know what we do with your personal information.
  * We don’t engage in activities that could jeopardise your trust.

"Personally identifying information" is information that individually identifies you, such as your name, physical address or email address. 

If you have any questions about this policy or your privacy, please contact us. 

### 1\. What does this policy do?

#### 1.1 This policy covers our "Services", meaning services or products by: 

**PriceMe** such the shopping comparison engine [PriceMe.co.nz](https://www.priceme.co.nz/) and its various subsites (Deals, Consumer etc.).  
**Merchant tool** for retailers.  
**Channelyser** data insights tool.  
**Partner sites** that PriceMe has white-labeled and that are hosted on a separate domain. 

#### 1.2 We are committed to your privacy and will comply with applicable privacy laws: 

including the [Privacy Act 1993​](http://www.legislation.govt.nz/act/public/1993/0028/232.0/DLM296645.html), any applicable Privacy Codes and other laws when dealing with your information.  
We will also comply with the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation to the extent that this applies to information we collect under a particular Service (e.g., if we target a particular Service at individuals living in the European Union). If you are an individual based in the European Union, you can email us to clarify how we treat your information.  

### 2\. What information do we collect?

We collect information so that we can provide you with our Services, and so that we can build new Services that make life easier for consumers when shopping online. We may collect the following personal information: 

#### 2.1 Information you give us, such as: 

**Account information**. When you sign up for a Service, we may require your name, username, password, email address or other personal information.  
**Profile information**. Certain Services may require you to complete a profile, which may include personal information such as your postal and delivery addresses, phone number. Parts of your profile (like your member number, user name, and feedback history) may be part of your public profile page, and will be publicly visible to others.  
**Application forms**. We collect information when you complete an application for any of our Services or for services that we connect to.  
**Listing content**. We collect the listing content when you list your products, which may include your description of the listing, photos and your user name. Listing content may include embedded information or other metadata.  
**Payment information**. PriceMe’s comparison service is free to use for regular consumers and no payment information is therefore not collected. However, we do collect financial information for retailers and brands (like your bank account or credit card information) that make payments to us or third parties using our Services (see below for how we use and hold this).  
**Communications and phone calls**. When you communicate with us or other Users in relation to a Service, we may collect information about your communication and any other information you provide.  
**Other information**. You may otherwise provide us information directly (by email or in other formats), such as when you provide feedback, fill in a form, conduct a search, update or add information to our Services, respond to surveys or other research activities, participate in promotions, upload into our Services or use other features of our Services. 

#### 2.2 Information we automatically collect, such as: 

**Usage information**. We collect information about your interactions with our Services, such as the pages or other content you view, your searches for products, price alerts and favourites that you have made, and emails and messages generated through your use of the Services.  
**Location information**. When you use certain features of our Services, we may collect different types of information about your general location (e.g. your physical or postal address or your device’s IP address) or more specific location information (e.g. precise location from your mobile GPS). Most mobile devices allow you to control or disable the use of location services for applications in the device’s settings menu.  
**Analytics**. We automatically collect analytics information when you use our Services, even if you have not created an account or logged in. We may use third party providers like Google Analytics to help us with this. Information collected includes, among other things: details about how you’ve used our Services (including links to third party applications), your IP address, access times, hardware and software information, device information, device event information (e.g. crashes, browser type), and the pages, applications or services you’ve viewed or engaged with before or after using our Services.  
**Transaction and financial Information**. We may collect information related to your transactions on our Services, including the date and time, amounts charged, and other related transaction details. Depending on your settings and the Services you use, we may collect financial information relating to your use of our Services and your financial history.  
**Via cookies and similar technologies**. We use cookies, pixels, beacons and other similar technologies to collect and store information about you when you use our Services (e.g. through Google Analytics or Google Tag Manager) and this collection may occur across devices. Cookies may be "session" cookies (which temporarily store information and expire when you close your browser) or "persistent" cookies (e.g. when you select "remember me" when logging in). We may also allow our business partners to use these technologies on our Services (e.g. for advertising and remarketing), or engage others to track your behaviour on our behalf. You may disable the usage of cookies through your browser settings and may opt out of certain advertising as described in clause 3.4 below. Some Services also use social media features (e.g. the Facebook Like button or widgets) which may collect your IP address and the pages you visit, and which are generally governed by the terms of the social media business providing the features. 

#### 2.3 Information from third parties or external sources, such as: 

**Information from third party services you use**. If you link, connect, or log in to your account with a third party service (e.g. Facebook), the third party service may send us information such as your registration and profile information from that service. This information varies and is controlled by that service or as authorised by you via your privacy settings at that service.  
**Background Information about you**. For some Services, to the extent permitted by applicable laws, we may request that you provide or are subject to background or credit checks, and we may obtain reports from public records (for example the Company’s office).  
**Analytics information**. We may collect analytics information from third parties (e.g. we may use Google Analytics, Google Analytics Demographics and Interest and Google AdWords. Analytics information is generally anonymised, but may include the device you’re using, the applications you use, your operating system, your IP address, and your geo-demographic information.  
**Advertising information**. Unless you have opted out, we may receive information about you and your activities on and off our Services through our partnerships, or about your experiences and interactions from our partner ad networks.  
**Information from public sources**. To the extent permitted by applicable law, we may receive additional information about you that is publicly available (e.g. we may collect your property information held by local councils for our Property Insights Service). 

### 3\. How do we use your information?

We use your personal information to provide you with Services. We also use your personal information with information from others so that we can analyse usage patterns across our data and improve our Services. We may use your personal information in the following ways: 

#### 3.1 To contact you about your account or use. 

**To enable your use of our Services**. We may enable you to communicate with other Users or make payments on our Services, verify your address.

We may contact you by phone, email, text message, instant message or otherwise (e.g. by "push notifications" on your mobile device, subject to your application settings) in relation to your account or use. With our emails you can:

  * Unsubscribe from emailed newsletters and advertising materials.
  * For most Services, change your email preferences for Service related emails, such as alerts and Watchlist reminders.

**Location information**. When you use certain features of our Services, we may collect different types of information about your general location (e.g. your physical or postal address or your device’s IP address) or more specific location information (e.g. precise location from your mobile GPS). Most mobile devices allow you to control or disable the use of location services for applications in the device’s settings menu.  
**Analytics**. We automatically collect analytics information when you use our Services, even if you have not created an account or logged in. We may use third party providers like Google Analytics to help us with this. Information collected includes, among other things: details about how you’ve used our Services (including links to third party applications), your IP address, access times, hardware and software information, device information, device event information (e.g. crashes, browser type), and the pages, applications or services you’ve viewed or engaged with before or after using our Services.  
**Transaction and financial Information**. We may collect information related to your transactions on our Services, including the date and time, amounts charged, and other related transaction details. Depending on your settings and the Services you use, we may collect financial information relating to your use of our Services and your financial history.  
**Via cookies and similar technologies**. We use cookies, pixels, beacons and other similar technologies to collect and store information about you when you use our Services (e.g. through Google Analytics or Google Tag Manager) and this collection may occur across devices. Cookies may be "session" cookies (which temporarily store information and expire when you close your browser) or "persistent" cookies (e.g. when you select "remember me" when logging in). We may also allow our business partners to use these technologies on our Services (e.g. for advertising and remarketing), or engage others to track your behaviour on our behalf. You may disable the usage of cookies through your browser settings and may opt out of certain advertising as described in clause 3.4 below. Some Services also use social media features (e.g. the Facebook Like button or widgets) which may collect your IP address and the pages you visit, and which are generally governed by the terms of the social media business providing the features. 

#### 3.2 To help provide our Services, for example: 

**To enable your use of our Services**. We may enable you to communicate with other Users or make payments on our Services, verify your address.

**To personalise or enrich our Services**. We may personalise, improve or enrich your experience by, among other things:

  * not asking you to log in unnecessarily (i.e. we may save your credentials for you);
  * delivering information you might be interested in, such as product recommendations and content specific to your interests;
  * showing ads based on your use of our Services and your preferences;
  * allowing you to create a profile, or creating a profile for you, for relevant Services. If we ever create a profile for you, you will be notified before your profile is activated and you will be able to update or deactivate your profile;

**To manage our Services**. We may provide, operate, protect, improve, optimise and otherwise manage our Services, including by using analytics, accounting and customer relationship management tools.  
**To conduct research**. We may conduct internal research in relation to Users’ demographics, interests, and behaviour to better understand and serve our community.  
**For training purposes**. We may use your personal information to help train and improve our staff who help provide or support the Services. 

#### 3.3 For trust, safety and assurance, for example to: 

**Protect the rights, property or safety of Users, third parties or us**. We may use your information to keep our Services safe, and to protect the rights and property of Users, third parties or us.  
**Ensure we comply with our obligations**. We will use information to ensure we comply with the law, including disclosures authorised under the [Privacy Act 1993​](http://www.legislation.govt.nz/act/public/1993/0028/232.0/DLM296645.html).  
**Enforce agreements**. We may use your information to enforce our agreements with Users or third parties.  
**Conduct investigations**. We may use your information to conduct investigations relating to our Services and make risk assessments.  
**Allow our business to be audited**. We may use your information to allow for auditing of our Services and businesses.  
**Verify the identity of users or third parties**. We may verify your identity or authenticate information provided by you, including information relating to others. 

#### 3.4 For advertising and marketing, for example to: 

**Send you promotional messages, marketing or advertising**. We may send you and other Users promotional messages, marketing, advertising, and other information. You authorise us to use your listing content for such purposes, including through display advertising, electronic direct mail or on social media. For clarity, products and services advertised on the websites which provide Services to you (e.g. display ads showing messages from third parties) are not endorsed by PriceMe.  
**Send you customised advertising (unless you opt out)**. We may send or show you promotional messages, marketing, advertising (including on-site display advertising), and other information that may be of interest to you based on your communication preferences (including information about campaigns and services of us or our business partners). We may make advertising space available through certain advertising platforms or exchanges, such as DoubleClick Ad Exchange, and you can manage what you see due to DoubleClick cookies through [Google’s Ad Settings​](https://support.google.com/dfp_premium/answer/2839090?hl=en). You may also be able to opt out of our advertising by visiting the websites of the the [Network Advertising Initiative​](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/) or [Digital Advertising Alliance​](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/). If you opt out of customised advertising, the advertising you see may be less relevant to you.  
**Run promotions**. We may use your information to administer referral programmes, rewards, surveys, contests, or other promotional activities or events sponsored or managed by us or our business partners.  
**Measure and improve our advertising**. We may use your information to measure the effectiveness of our advertising and make improvements. 

#### 3.5 To help you publish things on our website, such as: 

**Your public profile**. Parts of your public profile page, such as your user name may be publicly visible to others.  
**Your listing content**. We may make listing content publicly available on the applicable Service when you publish it (and in such cases, you are solely responsible for such publication). Listing content will also be available to people who use our API (e.g. developers) and may appear on other websites or applications.  
**Your feedback**. A number of our Services allow Users to provide feedback. These may be publicly available on our Services. 

#### 3.6 For other things, with your express consent. 

We may disclose your information at your direction, or otherwise as you agree with us. Please note that we:

  * Only use your credit card details for purposes related to your transactions and for fraud prevention or law enforcement purposes.

### 4\. Who do we disclose your information to?

We may need to disclose your personal information to others to provide you with our Services, to improve our Services or uphold the law or our terms. As described above, we may disclose your information to PriceMe Partner sites. We may also disclose your personal information in the following ways: 

#### 4.1 To our service providers, to provide and manage our Services. 

In order to provide and manage our Services, we may need to disclose some of your personal information to our third party service providers. These providers have limited access to your personal information to perform tasks on our behalf, and are contractually obliged to use your personal information consistently with this Privacy Policy. These disclosures will be consistent with the Service-specific terms and the rest of this privacy policy. 

#### 4.2 To other third parties, such as: 

**Advertisers providing customised ads, unless you opt out**. We may give advertisers your personal information to facilitate them sending you promotional messages, marketing, advertising, and other information that may be of interest to you (unless you unsubscribe). This may be provided on our Services or on services provided by those advertisers. The advertiser’s own privacy policy will apply to the personal information we send them. Depending on the privacy policy of the advertiser, the advertiser may combine the personal information we give them with personal information they hold about you, to assist with their advertising to you. This is particularly relevant for Google’s Customer Match and Facebook Customer Audience (it’s possible to opt out of both these programmes on Google’s and Facebook’s sites. If any personal information is shared, we require that it is done so securely. 

#### 4.3 To authorities or other entities to uphold the law or our terms, for example: 

**For legal compliance or law enforcement purposes**. We may disclose your personal information to courts, law enforcement or government agencies, or third parties, to the extent we believe that disclosure is appropriate or permitted by the Privacy Act.  
**To protect the rights, property or safety of us, our Users or others**. This includes collecting money you owe us and making such disclosures as are necessary for the purpose of trust, safety and assurance in accordance with clause 3.3 above. 

#### 4.4 To others where necessary to reorganise or sell our business. 

If we undertake or are involved in any merger, acquisition, reorganisation, sale of assets, bankruptcy, or insolvency event, then we may sell, transfer or share some or all of our assets. In this event, we will notify you before your personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. 

#### 4.5 To other third parties, where your identity is anonymised. 

We may share non-personally identifiable information (e.g., aggregated information about our Users that we combine together so that it no longer identifies or references an individual User), for industry and market analysis, demographic profiling, marketing and advertising, and other business purposes. 

#### 4.6 Also, some interactions with our sites and Services may be subject to additional third party terms. For example: 

**External links. Our Services may contain links to third party retailers, websites or services**. We don’t own or control those retailers, websites or services or endorse them in any way and, if you interact with them, you may be providing information directly to the third party concerned. The third parties will have their own rules about the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information. We encourage you to review their privacy policies accordingly.  
**Certain embedded third party services**. Some of our Services use embedded third party services, e.g. Google Maps. Use of those services may be subject to third party terms, e.g. Google Maps Additional Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy.  
**Information indexed by search engines**. Information you share publicly on our Services may be indexed through third party search engines. We do not control the practices of third party search engines, and they may use caches containing your outdated information. 

### 5\. How do we hold and protect your information?

We take your privacy seriously. We also work hard to ensure we keep your personal information safe and to avoid any harm to you or your personal information. We would notify you and related authorities if a potentially harmful data breach of your personal information did occur. We delete personal information after it is no longer reasonably necessary for us to use it. In particular: 

#### 5.1 We use industry recognised security practices and measures. 

We are committed to keeping your personal information as safe and secure as possible and follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.  
We continuously implement and update our administrative, technical, and physical security measures to help protect your personal information against unauthorised access, loss, destruction, or alteration. However, despite all of our measures we can’t 100% guarantee the security of the transmission or storage of your personal information. 

#### 5.2 We store your information in New Zealand or overseas subject to standards that will comply with our privacy obligations 

You authorise us to transfer, store, and process your personal information in New Zealand and possibly other countries. Where we store information overseas, or a third party we use to provide our Services stores information overseas (e.g. Amazon Web Services and Microsoft Azure), we will ensure that the storage complies with New Zealand privacy obligations. 

#### 5.3 We retain your information as long as reasonably required, unless we are legally required to hold it longer. 

We will keep your personal information for as long as is reasonably required for us to use it in accordance with this policy, unless we are required by law to hold it longer. In particular, we may retain:

  * All listing content after listings have expired. We do this for various reasons, including in case of disputes, to help prevent fraud and facilitate legal processes, to comply with financial record-keeping and to help personalise or recommend products in future. Listing content may also persist elsewhere when third parties access and cache listings while they are live. For example, Google do this when they index the web for searching and so old listings may show in Google searches for a period of time.
  * Other personal information that is deleted by you may persist for a limited time in our backup systems.

#### 5.4 Credit card Information is held subject to stringent payments industry standards. 

Credit and debit card information is sensitive and we protect it to stringent security standards, which at a minimum comply with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards ("PCI standards"). We use a number of procedures and different technologies to help protect your credit and debit card information from unauthorised access, use and disclosure. Our compliance with PCI is audited every year.  
For some Services we may allow you to save your card information for subsequent use (and, to make life easier for you, we may use your saved card information for other Services we offer where you’re able to make card payments). 

### 6\. How can I manage my information?

We know your circumstances, details and preferences will change. So, we’ve built a number of tools for you to manage your personal information. You can: 

#### 6.1 Update your information by: 

**Managing your profiles, where this is available**. Some of our Services allow you to build more customised profiles.  
**Updating your account information**. In most cases, you may review and update the account information we hold about you (such as your email address, and password) by logging into the relevant Service and updating the information in your account. If this isn’t available and you want to update your information, please get in touch with us.  
**Managing your listings, where allowed**. Some listings enable you to change the details that can be seen on our Services.  
**Managing your privacy options**. You can manage your information options using your user account page or by unsubscribing from an advertising email. Otherwise, please use the contact details for the applicable Service. 

#### 6.2 Ask us to update, provide or delete your information 

If you wish to access or correct any of your personal information, you can contact us directly. We will respond to your request promptly, and always within 20 working days. If you want us to delete any personal information you have submitted to us, please contact us. We will consider each request for deletion on a case by case basis taking into account the terms and conditions of the particular Service(s) and our legal obligations to retain certain information. Note that information that you have shared with others may continue to be publicly visible on our Services in association with your first name, even after your account is cancelled.  
If you want to cancel your account for any of our Services, please contact us. 

### 7\. How do we amend this policy?

#### We may make updates from time to time by a PriceMe site announcement or other notice, usually with two weeks’ notice or more.

Occasionally urgent changes will be required, but we will generally give you at least two weeks’ notice to review any changes, unless the Service-specific terms do not require notice of changes to them. For significant changes we may notify you directly via email. As we update this policy from time to time, we encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. 

### 8\. What do the terms in this policy mean?

#### 8.1 "User" 

User means anyone using our Services, including any PriceMe member. 

#### 8.2 "personal information" 

Personal information means information about an identifiable individual, as defined by the [Privacy Act 1993​](http://www.legislation.govt.nz/act/public/1993/0028/232.0/DLM296645.html). 

#### 8.3 "Services" 

Services means our Services, as defined in clause 1.1. 

#### 8.4 "PriceMe Partner Services" 

PriceMe Partner Services means any product or service (other than those described in clause 1.1 as being provided by PriceMe) that is provided by an entity that PriceMe operates, unless a particular PriceMe Partner Service has its own privacy policy. 

#### 8.5 "we", "us" or "our" 

We, us, or our means: (a) PriceMe, Price Me Limited and PriceMe International Ltd. 

#### 8.6 "you" or "your" 

You or your, in relation to any personal information, means any individual who is identifiable from the personal information.
